Thus far in the lesson,
到目前为止
we've only looked at relationships between quantitative variables.
我们只研究了数值变量之间的关系
We'll now look at the relationship between our fuel efficiency
现在我们来研究燃油效率
variable against the qualitative variable, Vehicle class.
与车辆类型这个分类变量的关系
Note here that I've used Pandas as type function to convert the V class column from
注意 这里我用了 Pandas 的函数 astype 将列 Vclass
a plain object type into
从 object 类型
an ordered categorical type putting the classes in order of size.
转换成有序分类类型 按大小对车辆类型进行了排列
This way, the sorting of levels is automatic and I
这样一来 类别会自动排序
won't need a second order parameter in my visualization calls.
我就不需要在调用可视化函数时再设一个排序参数了
The prototype I'll be going over in this video is the violin plot.
这次我要绘制小提琴图
When we use seaborn's violin plot function in
在使用 seaborn 的 violinplot 函数时
the usual way setting the data x and y variables,
如果我们只设置参数 data、x 和 y
we get the following plot.
就会得到这样的图表
We should clean this up a little bit first.
看来我们得调整一下
I'm going to use the color palette function to make sure each level is
使用 color_palette 函数获取一种颜色来表示各类别
the same color and the Xticks function to slightly rotate the labels.
再用 xticks 函数稍微旋转一下标签
For now, I'm also going to set
现在 我要设参数 inner 为 None
the inner equals none parameter to clean up the middle of the plots.
先去掉图形中间的内容
I'll get back to this parameter later on.
稍后我会细讲这个参数
For each of the vehicle classes,
对应每一种车辆类型
an area is plotted that shows the approximate density
图表中的每个区域大致体现了
of efficiency values for each vehicle class.
各车辆类型的效率值密度
They're like density curves turned on their sides.
有点像是侧面视角的密度曲线
From this plot, we can see that there isn't
由图可知
a monotonic relationship between car size and fuel efficiency.
汽车大小与燃油效率的关系并不单一
The largest cars seem to have the lowest fuel efficiencies,
虽然最大的汽车燃油效率最低
but the longtail suggest outliers with the highest of efficiencies.
但这条长尾巴意味着该车型在最高效率处有异常值
Mini compact and subcompact cars have
微型车和小型车
the next best efficiencies but
的燃油效率为第二高
the distribution for mini compact cars is much more peaked.
但微型车的分布有更多峰值
Finally, compact and midsize cars have
最后 紧凑型车和中型车
the best efficiencies but the distribution of
的燃油效率最高
the midsize cars is broader than the compacts.
但中型车的分布要比紧凑型的广
Let's briefly go back to the plot without the inner equals non parameter setting.
现在我们来简单讲讲不设参数 inner 为 None 的情况
The thing that is plotted in each violin is a miniature box plot.
小提琴里多出来的东西其实是小型箱线图
A box plot is another quantitative versus qualitative
箱线图也能表示数值变量和分类变量的关系
plot type that takes a summary approach to displaying the data.
绘制时 这类图表会进行数据汇总统计
I'll give more details about box plots in the next video.
详情请见下一视频